(Music) This is the human test,
( موسيقى ) هذا اختبار للبشر ،
a test to see if you are a human.
اختبار لنرى فيما إذا كنت بشرياً .
Please raise your hand if something applies to you.
رجاءاً ارفع يدك اذا انطبق شئ عليك .
Are we agreed? Yes?
هل نحن متفقون ؟ نعم ؟
Then let's begin.
دعونا نبدأ .
Have you ever eaten a booger
هل سبق وأن أكلت مخاطاً
long past your childhood?
في السابق أثناء طفولتك ؟
(Laughter)
( ضحك )
It's okay, it's safe here.
لا تقلق ، المكان آمنٌ هنا .
Have you ever made a small, weird sound
هل سبق وأن أصدرت صوتاً منخفضاً ، وغريباً
when you remembered something embarrassing?
عند تذكرك أمراً محرجاً ؟
Have you ever purposely lowercased
هل سبق وأن قمت عمداً بتصغير
the first letter of a text
الحرف الاول من النص
in order to come across as sad or disappointed?
في سبيل تخطي حزن أو خذلان ؟
(Laughter)
( ضحك )
Okay.
جيد .
Have you ever ended a text with a period
هل سبق وأن أنهيت النص بفاصلة
as a sign of aggression? Okay. Period.
كعلامة للعدوانية ؟ جيد . فاصلة .
Have you ever laughed or smiled
هل سبق وأن ضحكت أو ابتسمت
when someone said something shitty to you
عندما قال لك شخص أمراً سيئاً
and then spent the rest of the day
ثم قضيت بعدها بقية يومك
wondering why you reacted that way?
وأنت تتساءل لماذا تفاعلت بتلك الطريقة ؟
Yes.
نعم .
Have you ever seemed to lose your airplane ticket
هل سبق وأن بدا لك أنك ستفقد تذكرت سفرك
a thousand times as you walked
ألف مرة وأنت تمشي
from the check-in to the gate?
من إنهاء إجراءاتك إلى البوابة ؟
Yes.
نعم .
Have you ever put on a pair of pants
هل سبق وأن ارتديت سروالين
and then much later realized that there was
ثم لاحقاً تنبهت أن هنالك
a loose sock smushed up against your thigh?
جورب فضفاض محشور على فخذك ؟
(Laughter)
( ضحك )
Good.
جيد .
Have you ever tried to guess someone else's password
هل سبق وأن حاولت تخمين كلمة المرور لشخص آخر
so many times that it locked their account?
عدة مرات إلى أن أُغلق حسابه ؟
Mmm.
ممم .
Have you ever had a nagging feeling that one day
هل سبق وأن ساورك شعور ملازم بأنك يوماً ما
you will be discovered as a fraud?
ستكشف على أنك مخادع ؟
Yes, it's safe here.
نعم ، المكان آمن هنا .
Have you ever hoped that there was some ability
هل سبق وأن أملت أن هنالك قدرة خفية
you hadn't discovered yet
لم تكتشفها بعد
that you were just naturally great at?
وأنك تتقنها بشكل طبيعي ؟
Mmm.
ممم .
Have you ever broken something in real life,
هل سبق وأن كسرت شيئاً في الحياة الواقعية ،
and then found yourself looking
وبعدها وجدت نفسك تبحث
for an "undo" button in real life?
عن زر " تراجع " في الحياة الواقعية ؟
Have you ever misplaced your TED badge
هل سبق أن أضعت بطاقة TED خاصتك
and then immediately started imagining
وبعدها مباشرة بدأت تتخيل
what a three-day Vancouver vacation might look like?
كيف تبدو 3 أيام إجازة في فانكوفر ؟
Have you ever marveled
هل سبق أن تعجبت
at how someone you thought was so ordinary
كيف لأحد كنت تعتقد أنه عادي جداً
could suddenly become so beautiful?
أن يصبح فجأة جميلاً جداً ؟
Have you ever stared at your phone
هل سبق وأن حدقت في هاتفك المحمول
smiling like an idiot while texting with someone?
وأنت تبتسم مثل الأحمق أثناء مراسلة شخص ما ؟
Have you ever subsequently texted that person
هل سبق أن أرسلت لذلك الشخص بعدها
the phrase "I'm staring at the phone
الجملة التالية " أنا أحدق في هاتفي
smiling like an idiot"?
وأبتسم مثل الأحمق " ؟
Have you ever been tempted to,
هل سبق وأن انتابتك رغبة ،
and then gave in to the temptation,
ثم انصعت لتلك الرغبة ،
of looking through someone else's phone?
بالنظر إلى هاتف شخص آخر ؟
Have you ever had a conversation with yourself
هل سبق وأن أجريت حواراً مع نفسك
and then suddenly realized
وفجأة أدركت
you're a real asshole to yourself?
أنك نذل حقيقي بالنسبة لنفسك ؟
(Laughter)
( ضحك )
Has your phone ever run out of battery
هل سبق وأن فرغت بطارية هاتفك
in the middle of an argument,
في وسط نقاش حاد ،
and it sort of felt like the phone
ثم بدا وكأن الهاتف
was breaking up with both of you?
يحاول الانفصال عنكما ؟
Have you ever thought
هل سبق وأن فكرت
that working on an issue between you was futile
أن العمل على أمرٍ بالنسبة لك كان بلا جدوى
because it should just be easier than this,
لأنه من المفترض أن يكون أسهل من هذا ،
or this is supposed to happen just naturally?
أو يفترض أن يحدث بطريقة طبيعية ؟
Have you ever realized that very little, in the long run,
هل سبق وأن أدركت أن القليل جداً ، على المدى الطويل ،
just happens naturally?
يحدث بشكل طبيعي ؟
Have you ever woken up blissfully
هل سبق وأن استيقظت بسلام
and suddenly been flooded by the awful remembrance
وفجأة غمرتك ذكرى مفزعة
that someone had left you?
بأن شخصاً قد هجرك ؟
Have you ever lost the ability to imagine a future
هل سبق وأن فقدت القدرة على تخيل المستقبل
without a person
بدون الشخص
that no longer was in your life?
الذي لم يعد موجوداً في حياتك ؟
Have you ever looked back on that event
هل سبق وأن نظرت إلى الخلف لذلك الحدث
with the sad smile of autumn
بابتسامة خريف حزينة
and the realization that futures will happen
مدركاً أن المستقبل سيحدث
regardless?
بغض النظر عنها ؟
Congratulations.
مبروك .
You have now completed the test.
لقد أنهيت الامتحان الآن .
You are all human.
أنتم جميعاً كائنات بشرية .
(Applause)
( تصفيق )